hach.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy Policy | Hach

WE UPDATED OUR PRIVACY NOTICE EFFECTIVE SEPTEMBER 25th, 2017

This Online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how Hach (“Hach”) handles personal information provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Hach that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Hach Sites”).

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Hach Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites linked from Hach Sites.

### **Information We Collect**

Hach collects the following types of information through the Hach Sites:

  * **Information you provide. Personal Information** you provide when registering for our products and services, responding to questionnaires or surveys, or contacting Hach customer service.
  * **Information collected automatically.** Your IP address and non-identifying information about your use of Hach Sites may be collected automatically using tracking technologies, such as cookies. Your website browser software can be set to reject all cookies; however, cookies can allow you to take advantage of some of the site’s essential features, which may not work if you reject cookies.
  * **Information collected from other sources.** We may combine information about you from Hach Sites, information collected offline or from external parties.

### **How We Use Your Information**

Hach uses the information we collect for several purposes, mainly:

  * To provide you with the Hach product and services you request.
  * To offer and provide information about related products and services
  * To customize and improve your experienceon Hach Sites.
  * To generally improve our products and Hach Sites and other internal business purposes.

### **Information we Share**

Hach does not sell or disclose your personal information to unrelated third parties without your consent, except:

  * To affiliates and third-party service providers to provide services and information on our sites, including online marketing and advertising, and to support our business operations. We require these parties to handle personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * To affiliates to offer and provide information about related products and services. We require these parties to handle personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * To another company in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the Hach’s affiliates.
  * To governing regulatory authorities, including the US Food and Drug Administration, or as may otherwise be necessary for Hach to comply with a legal obligation or demand.

### **Your Privacy Choices**

If you have questions about this Privacy Notice, if you want to change your personal information, or if you would like to opt-out of a Hach online program, please contact us by clicking on the “Contact Us” link on the Hach Site you are using, by using the Hach contact information on the Hach mobile application you are using, or by emailing us at [dataprivacy@Hach.com](mailto:privacy@Danaher.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

    Hach

    Attn: Privacy

    PO Box 389

    Loveland, CO 80539

### **Security**

Hach maintains controls to protect and secure personal information, but when you share personal information online there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could gain access to your information.

### **Accessing Our Sites Globally**

By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.

### **Changes to Our Privacy Notice**

Check this Privacy Notice regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.

## **Hach Online Privacy Policy**

EFFECTIVE SEPTEMBER 25th, 2017

This Online Privacy Notice (“Privacy Policy”) explains how we handle the personal information provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Hach Corporation, 2200 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW. Suite 800W Washington, DC 20037USA, that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Hach Sites”).

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Hach Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party Web sites to which Hach Sites may link.

## **Types of Information We Collect Online**

The types of personal information that we may collect while you use the Hach Sites are described in this section and include both information that you provide to us and information that we collect automatically when you use the Hach Sites.

For purposes of this Privacy Notice, “ **Personal Information** ” means information that identifies you or that could reasonably be used to identify you. Examples of Personal Information include name, address, telephone number, and email address.

## **Information You Provide**

You do not have to register for a service or program to receive much of the information available through Hach Sites. However, some of our content is available only to registered or identified users and will require you to set up a profile or provide specific information about yourself in order to provide you the service.

## **Personal Information You Provide When Visiting Hach Sites**

Hach collects Personal Information that you provide on Hach Sites, for example, when purchasing a product, to receive marketing products and information, contact Hach customer service, or respond to Hach questionnaires or surveys. This could include:

  * Contact Information such as your name, address, phone number, or email address
  * Registration Information such as your username and password
  * Remuneration information when you provide a service to Hach in your capacity as a healthcare professional
  * Employment, education and other background information when you inquire about employment with Hach
  * Payment information (such as banking information, payment card number, expiration date, delivery address, and billing address)
  * Content you may provide (for example, when you complete our Online Contact Form or submit other information).

**Personal Information You Share During Other Interactions with Hach**

You may contact Hach to ask questions, discuss your concerns, or report issues regarding our products. If you communicate with or request information from Hach, you may be prompted to provide your contact information as well as any personal information that is relevant to your request.

### **Information That May Be Collected Automatically**

When you use the Hach Sites, we also may collect certain usage and device information automatically as described below.

### **IP Address**

We may record the Internet Protocol (“IP”) address of your computer or other electronic device when you visit the Hach Sites. An IP address identifies the electronic device you use to access the Sites, which allows us to maintain communication with your computer as you move about Hach Sites and to customize content.

### **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

We also collect information about your use of Hach Sites through tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons. A “cookie” is a unique numeric code that is transferred to your computer to track your interests and preferences and to recognize you as a return visitor. A “Web beacon” is a transparent graphic image placed on a Web site, e-mail or advertisement that enables the monitoring of things such as user activity and site traffic. These technologies help remember your preferences and allow us to bring you the content and features that are likely to be of greatest interest to you on the basis of “clickstream” data that shows your previous activities on Hach Sites.

We utilize Google Display Advertising (such as Retargeting with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting) to (1) show you our ads on other websites based on your prior visits to Hach Sites, and (2) better understand our ad impressions and use of ad services. In connection with the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting service, we may use data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to understand and improve our marketing campaigns and Site content.

Some of our online advertising takes place through Google Display Advertising. As part of this program, we use Google Analytics features such as Retargeting. In connection with that feature and others offered by ad networks, we and the operators of ad networks, including Google, may use third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) – and in some cases first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) – to inform, optimize and serve ads across the Internet, based on a user's past visits to Hach Sites. We also may show you ads from some of our affiliated companies when you visit Hach Sites.

You can opt out of Google Ads by visiting <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>. If you do not want your data used by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at the [Google Analytics opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

This Hach Site is not designed to respond to "do not track" signals received from browsers.

To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies, including how to disable them, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our Sites and deleting or disabling them will reduce the site’s functionality.

### **Mobile Tracking**

Some Hach Sites are available either as mobile applications or mobile sites that you can use on your mobile device. If you use a mobile device to access and use the Hach Sites, we may collect the following mobile-specific information in addition to the other information described above: device or advertising ID, device type, hardware type, media access control (“MAC”) address, international mobile equipment identity (“IMEI”), the version of your mobile operating system, the platform used to access or download the Hach Site (e.g., Apple, Google, Amazon, Windows), location information and usage information about your device and your use of the Hach Sites.

### **Information Collected from Other Sources**

We may combine information about you from a visit to one Hach Site with information about you from visits to other Hach Sites. We may also combine information about you that is collected through the Hach Sites with information that we have collected offline, as well as with information provided to us by third parties.

## **How We Use Your Information**

We use your Personal Information to provide you the product and services you request, communicate with you, improve your experience on the Hach Sites, generally improve our products and services and for other internal business purposes, as described in more detail below.

### **Providing Product and Services You Request**

If you choose to purchase a product or receive our services, we use the Personal Information that you provide through Hach Sites to manage your orders and invoices, to process payments, to respond to your questions, provide you the services you request and offer an optimal customer experience.

### **Marketing**

You may also receive marketing information from Hach and related affiliates, such as offers regarding Hach related products or services, invitations to participate in surveys about our products, or notifications about special promotions. In such cases, we will use your contact and other Personal Information to send you marketing information.

### **Customized User Experiences**

The Personal Information that you provide may be used to create customized offers, information, or services tailored to your interests and preferences. Also, we may use your IP address and the data that we obtain automatically through the use of cookies or similar tracking technologies to make our Hach Sites easier to use and navigate as well as to personalize the content provided on Hach Sites by anticipating the information and services that may be of interest to you.

### **Business and Product Improvement**

In order to discover new facts that could help Hach better understand customer needs and help improve, develop, and evaluate product, services, materials, and programs. Hach analyzes the information that you have provided. For these purposes Hach does not use information that can directly identify you.

### **Site Analytics and Improvement**

We may use the information that you provide and the information we collect automatically about your use of the Hach Sites to monitor user traffic patterns and preferences for site improvement, analytics and optimization.

## **Information We Share**

We only share your Personal Information with third parties as described below. We do not sell or rent Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes.

### **Third-Party Advertising and Online Behavioral Advertising**

You may be provided with online advertisements of Hach products and services on third-party websites and mobile services that are tailored to you, for example, on the basis of information that you provide to Hach or a third-party website you are visiting, or of your browsing activity, purchases, or interests. These types of tailored online advertisements may come through several sources, such as the following:

  * We may share with our advertising service providers your non-identifying information that we have obtained from cookies and other tracking technologies on our Hach Sites.
  * Some Hach Sites participate in online behavioral advertising (this is also sometimes called re-target advertising or interest-based advertising). You can identify these sites by the “Advertising Choices” link in the footer. Our advertising network partners may place and use cookies on Hach Web sites and on other third-party Web sites to collect information about your activities in order to provide you with online advertisements that are based on your interests. When a Hach online behavioral advertisement is delivered to you, you will see an “Ad Choices” icon. Clicking on the icon or link will take you to a Web site where you can manage or opt out of the use of data about your browsing history that is used for the delivery of online behavioral advertisements. If you opt out, you may still see advertisements online, including advertisements from Hach that are based on other information (e.g., based on the content of the page being viewed rather than your prior clickstream activity). In some cases, data may still be collected about your browsing activity by these third-party advertisers, but they will not use this data to deliver advertisements that are based on your past online browsing behavior. 
  * Some Web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to Web sites with which the browser communicates. As of the Effective Date of this Privacy Notice, an industry standard has not yet been established on how to respond to these signals. Therefore, Hach does not currently respond to these signals. As discussed above, you can opt-out from advertisers that use your browsing history to deliver online behavioral advertisements by visiting adchoices.

### **Affiliates, Vendors and Suppliers**

We have relationships with various vendors and suppliers, including our affiliated companies, who help us operate our business and for whom it may be necessary to have access to your Personal Information in the course of providing services to Hach and its related affiliates. We will not authorize these parties to use your Personal Information for any purpose that is not related to Hach and its related affiliates business operation, and we require them to handle your Personal Information collected through the Hach Sites in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

### **Co-branded Sites**

We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or “co-branded” basis. At a co‑branded site, you will see both the Hach logo and the logo of the co-branding partner displayed on your screen. You should read the individual privacy policies of our co-branding partners, as they may differ in some respects from ours. Reading these policies will help you to make an informed decision about whether to provide your information to a given site.

### **Product Reports**

If you contact Hach regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information that you provide in submitting reports to the designated government regulatory authority, such as the US Food and Drug Administration and as otherwise required of us by law.

### **Legal Rights and Obligations**

In certain limited circumstances, Hach may need to disclose your Personal Information in order to comply with a legal obligation or demand, such as to comply with reporting obligations to our governing regulatory authorities regarding the safety of our products, or in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the Hach Sites. In such instances, we will take measures to protect your Personal Information to the extent possible. We also reserve the right to use Personal Information to investigate and prosecute users who violate our rules or who engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to others or to others’ property.

## **Children Privacy**

Hach does not knowingly collect or use any personal information directly from children (we define “children” as minors younger than 13) on Hach Sites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, to communicate with us, or to use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

## **Your Privacy Choices**

You may contact us at any time if you have questions about this Privacy Notice or the Personal Information we collect about you. You can also opt-out or unsubscribe from any of our services.

Please contact us by clicking on the “Contact Us” link, by using the Hach contact information on the Hach mobile application, or by emailing us at [dataprivacy@hach.com](mailto:privacy@Danaher.com) . Alternatively, you may send a letter to the

following address:

Hach

Attn: Privacy

PO Box 389

Loveland, CO 80539

In all communications to Hach, please include your email address, the Web site address, mobile application, and/or the specific Hach product to which you provided Personal Information ( _e.g._ , Hach.com), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete, amend, or correct your Personal Information and are contacting us by email, please put “Deletion Request” or “Amendment/Correction Request” in the subject line of the email. We will respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner and may need to further confirm your identity in order to process certain requests.

## **Data Security**

Hach maintains reasonable technical, administrative and physical controls to secure any Personal Information collected through the Hach Sites. However, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could intercept an Internet transmission, or that someone will find a way to thwart our security systems. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting Personal Information over the Internet, especially your financial-related information. Hach cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your Personal Information; therefore, when submitting Personal Information to Hach Sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks.

## **Third Party Sites and Social Media Plug-ins**

This Privacy Notice does not apply to Hach Sites that do not link to this Privacy Notice, or to third-party Web sites to which Hach Sites may link. Hach Sites may use social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook “Like” button, “Share to Twitter” button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit Hach Sites, the operator of the social plug-in can place a cookie on your computer or other electronic device that enables that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our Site. If you are logged into the social media Web site (e.g., Facebook, Twitter) while browsing on our Hach Site, the social media plug-in allows that social media Web site to receive information that you have visited our Hach Site. The social media plug-in also allows the social media Web site to share information about your activities on our Hach Site with other users of their social media Web site. These sharing settings are managed by the social media Web site and governed by its privacy policy.

### **Accessing Our Sites Globally**

This site is owned and operated by Hach in the United States, but the information you provide will be accessible to our affiliates, vendors, and suppliers in other countries. Furthermore, if you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your communication with us will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international borders. The level of legal protection for personal information is not the same in all countries; however, we will take the security measures described in this Privacy Notice in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.

**Notice to California Residents**

Subject to certain limits under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us at [privacy@Hach.com](mailto:privacy@danaher.com).

### **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We will only use Personal Information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy in effect when the information was collected from you or as authorized by you. However, and subject to any applicable consent requirements, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page with a new effective date. Hach encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Any Personal Information collected upon your continued use of Hach Sites will be handled in accordance with the currently-posted Privacy Policy.
